<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Critical Thinking on Randy Ridenour</title>
    <link>http://randyridenour.net/tags/critical-thinking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Critical Thinking on Randy Ridenour</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Randy Ridenour</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 13:18:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://randyridenour.net/tags/critical-thinking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Disagreement and Being Wrong</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2017/01/09/disagreement-and-being-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 13:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2017/01/09/disagreement-and-being-wrong/</guid>
      <description>This internet meme has been making the rounds lately:
The graphic shows two people on opposite ends of an ambiguous figure on the ground. One person points down and says &amp;ldquo;Six.&amp;rdquo; The other points down, saying &amp;ldquo;Nine.&amp;rdquo; The original caption is &amp;ldquo;Just because you are right, does not mean I am wrong.&amp;rdquo; That caption is crossed out, and this rebuttal placed below:
 But one of those people is wrong, someone painted a six or nine, they need to back up ad orient themselves, see if there are any other numbers to alight with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of Fake News</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2016/12/03/the-rise-of-fake-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 10:28:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2016/12/03/the-rise-of-fake-news/</guid>
      <description>NPR has a fascinating, if not troubling, interview with a creator of various fake news sites that began to profilerate during the 2016 presidential election. This part of the interview was particularly telling:
 Well, this isn&amp;rsquo;t just a Trump-supporter problem. This is a right-wing issue. Sarah Palin&amp;rsquo;s famous blasting of the lamestream media is kind of record and testament to the rise of these kinds of people. The post-fact era is what I would refer to it as.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confirmation Bias and the Clinton Foundation</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2016/10/21/the-clinton-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 06:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2016/10/21/the-clinton-foundation/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I showed that claiming that only 5.7% of Clinton Foundation donations goes to charity is essentially false. Although that is indeed the percentage that goes to other charitable organizations, it ignores the fact that the Clinton Foundation is itself a public charity, unlike the Trump Foundation, which is a private foundation.
In response, a friend said that, although my claim was technically true, the majority of Clinton Foundation money goes back to the Clintons through the its two largest program expenditures, the Clinton Global Initiative (CGI) and the Clinton Presidential Library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Uselessness of Political Fact-Checking</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2016/10/20/the-uselessness-of-political-factchecking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 19:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2016/10/20/the-uselessness-of-political-factchecking/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that political fact-checking is largely useless. Either people completely ignore the work of fact-checkers, or the fact-checkers ignore the relevant facts. Today, I saw a claim that Clinton had leaked classified information about the nuclear response window. What was curious was that the post included a link to a snopes.com story explaining that the supposed leak was not classified, but was already public information. The person evidently failed to read the very story to which they had linked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Race, Police Shooting, and Probability</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2016/10/01/black-lives-matter-and-conditional-probabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2016/10/01/black-lives-matter-and-conditional-probabilities/</guid>
      <description>I just read a Facebook comment by someone who was apparently downplaying the Black Lives Matter movement by pointing out that the police shoot more white Americans than black Americans.
True, but it&amp;rsquo;s a classic error in statistical reasoning. The vast majority of drivers involved in accidents are sober, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t follow that one is more likely to have an accident if one is sober than if drunk. That is, the probability that a person was drunk given that he was in an accident is very low, but the probability that someone will be in an accident given that he is drunk is very high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go to Your Pastor for Depression?</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2015/08/13/go-to-your-pastor-for-depression/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2015/08/13/go-to-your-pastor-for-depression/</guid>
      <description>Glennon Doyle Melton at momastery.com posted an article with the provocative title, &amp;ldquo;If You Wouldn’t Go to Your Minister for a Mammogram, Don’t Go for Depression.&amp;rdquo; In it, she makes the important point that there are those in Christian communities that advocate treatment of depression through prayer alone, refusing to see it as a medical condition, yet those same people would not treat cancer simply with prayer. In this, I wholeheartedly agree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NRA Survey</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2015/01/20/nra-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 10:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2015/01/20/nra-survey/</guid>
      <description>I just received a call from the National Rifle Association today. A recorded message from the NRA Executive Vice-President concerning the U.N. Small Arms Treaty was followed by the following single question survey:
 Do you think it&amp;rsquo;s OK for the U.N. to be on our soil attacking our gun rights?
 I was instructed to press &amp;ldquo;1&amp;rdquo; if I did not think was OK for the U.N. to be on our soil attacking our gun rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Biases Song</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/05/05/this-is-a-song-by-a-hs-psychology-teacher-designed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 19:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/05/05/this-is-a-song-by-a-hs-psychology-teacher-designed/</guid>
      <description>This is a song by a HS Psychology teacher designed to help students learn about cognitive biases. Play it in the background as you study for the Critical Thinking final.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change Blindness</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2009/12/14/another-change-blindness-demonstration-i-have-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 21:47:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2009/12/14/another-change-blindness-demonstration-i-have-to/</guid>
      <description>Another change blindness demonstration. I have to admit that this one fooled me.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change Blindness</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2009/12/14/change-blindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 21:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2009/12/14/change-blindness/</guid>
      <description>A great experiment that shows how little we tend to perceive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Car Accidents and Conditional Probabilities</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2009/10/21/car-accidents-and-conditional-probabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2009 21:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2009/10/21/car-accidents-and-conditional-probabilities/</guid>
      <description>A problem we looked at in Critical Thinking today asked why most car accidents occur close to home. The answer is that most of our driving is close to home. The problem then asked us to explain that in terms of conditional probabilities. I don&#39;t think that I explained it very well, so let me take another shot at it.
Remember the definition of conditional probability: Pr(A|B) = Pr(A&amp;amp;B)/Pr(B).
Let&#39;s assume that 90% of driving is close to home and 10% is not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expectations and Grades</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2009/02/19/expectations-and-grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 12:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2009/02/19/expectations-and-grades/</guid>
      <description>There’s an interesting piece in the New York Times today about student expectations and grade inflation. Apparently, there are students (at institutions other than Oklahoma Baptist, I’m sure) that believe that doing the minimal work that is required of everyone in the course should be sufficient to earn a B for the course. Either we have lowered the level of work that we are willing to consider average, or it really is true that in today’s society someone who manages to complete the minimum requirements really is above average.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Monty Hall Problem</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/11/18/the-monty-hall-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2008 22:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/11/18/the-monty-hall-problem/</guid>
      <description>One of the assignments in Critical Thinking was to figure the probability of winning the prize in the traditional three-door Monty Hall problem. Remember that there are three doors for you, the contestant, to choose from, but only one has the prize. The host knows what door the prize is behind, and opens another door to show you that there is nothing there. He will open neither the one you pick nor the one that has the prize.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change and Objectivity</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/06/02/climate-change-and-objectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2008 22:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/06/02/climate-change-and-objectivity/</guid>
      <description>The Washington Post reports something today that is unfortunate but unsurprising. NASA&#39;s inspector general has determined that political appointees have controlled and distorted information about research on climate change conducted by NASA scientists. This is why it is so difficult for the layperson like myself to make informed decisions about the severity of the problem and the best response to the problem. Such decisions should be made on the basis of the best science, but what we know about the science has been distorted by those who have already decided what is to be done.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>