<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching on Randy Ridenour</title>
    <link>http://randyridenour.net/tags/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teaching on Randy Ridenour</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Randy Ridenour</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 11:24:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://randyridenour.net/tags/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2017 Textbooks</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2017/06/27/fall-2017-textbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 11:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2017/06/27/fall-2017-textbooks/</guid>
      <description>Here are the textbooks for my Fall 2017 courses:
Introduction to Philosophy Adler, Jonathan E., and Catherine Z. Elgin. 2007. Philosophical Inquiry: Classic and Contemporary Readings. Indianapolis, IN: Hackett Publishing.  Critical Thinking None required to purchase.
History of Ancient Philosophy Reeve, C. D. C., and Patrick L. Miller. 2006. Introductory Readings in Ancient Greek and Roman Philosophy. Indianapolis, IN: Hackett Pub. Co. Shields, Christopher. 2011. Ancient Philosophy: A Contemporary Introduction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancient Philosophy Study Guide</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2016/09/26/ancient-philosophy-study-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 08:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2016/09/26/ancient-philosophy-study-guide/</guid>
      <description>What is the reason for separating Plato&amp;rsquo;s dialogues into Socratic (early) and Platonic (middle) dialogues? Why is Socrates’ method primarily negative? Is there anything that Socrates does (at least implicitly) claim to know? Explain why the Meno is considered a transitional dialogue. Explain Meno&amp;rsquo;s Paradox. How does Plato respond? Although Socrates claims ignorance, he seems to hold some surprising philosophical positions. Explain. Why did Socrates not plead for his life?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice for Those About to be Tested</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2015/02/11/advice-for-those-about-to-be-tested/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 07:37:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2015/02/11/advice-for-those-about-to-be-tested/</guid>
      <description>Therefore I beg you, reader, not to rejoice too greatly if you have read much, but if you have understood much. Nor that you have understood much, but that you have been able to retain it. Otherwise it is of little profit either to read or to understand.”  Hugh of Saint Victor, d. Feb. 11, 1141</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explain Everything</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2015/01/13/explain-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 17:38:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2015/01/13/explain-everything/</guid>
      <description>An Apple education representative recommended the iOS app &amp;ldquo;Explain Everything.&amp;rdquo; I imported a Keynote presentation, talked through it, then posted the result to YouTube. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take any time at all. Explain Everything looks like it will be a great tool for anyone teaching in a distance learning context.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Keynote in Class</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2011/11/30/using-keynote-in-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 11:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2011/11/30/using-keynote-in-class/</guid>
      <description>I have been using Keynote for iOS for lecture presentations in classes this semester. The process has been so easy, that this is the first semester that I have consistently used slide presentations during lectures. Most of my presentations were initially prepared on the Mac, then imported into Keynote for iOS on the iPad. Keynote for iOS seems to be fairly adept at importing transitions and effects. My only complaint is that the default font used in my preferred theme is different in the iOS version than in the desktop version of Keynote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coconut</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2011/03/30/i-received-an-interesting-package-in-campus-mail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 17:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2011/03/30/i-received-an-interesting-package-in-campus-mail/</guid>
      <description>I received an interesting &#34;package&#34; in campus mail yesterday. It&#39;s a coconut with my name and box number written on it. There wasn&#39;t a note attached, so I really don&#39;t know what the significance of this is. Any ideas?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep Deprivation</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2011/03/17/sleep-deprivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 19:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2011/03/17/sleep-deprivation/</guid>
      <description>This is for all my students who send me emails at 3:00 in the morning.
From Tony Schwarz&#39;s post titled &#34;Sleep is More Important than Food&#34; at the Harvard Business Review:
 &amp;hellip;In reality, the research suggests that even small amounts of sleep deprivation take a significant toll on our health, our mood, our cognitive capacity and our productivity.
Many of the effects we suffer are invisible. Insufficient sleep, for example, deeply impairs our ability to consolidate and stabilize learning that occurs during the waking day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1895 Eighth Grade Final Exam</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2011/02/23/1895-eighth-grade-final-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2011 02:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2011/02/23/1895-eighth-grade-final-exam/</guid>
      <description>On the NY Times site, Stephen Dubner posted a final exam given to eighth grade students in Salina, Kansas in 1895. I&amp;rsquo;d rather not talk about how I would have done on the exam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did I Miss Anything?</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/09/08/did-i-miss-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 14:10:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/09/08/did-i-miss-anything/</guid>
      <description>A poetic answer to that perennial question from those who were absent from class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Biases Song</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/05/05/this-is-a-song-by-a-hs-psychology-teacher-designed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 19:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/05/05/this-is-a-song-by-a-hs-psychology-teacher-designed/</guid>
      <description>This is a song by a HS Psychology teacher designed to help students learn about cognitive biases. Play it in the background as you study for the Critical Thinking final.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro Essay 1</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2009/09/16/intro-essay-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2009 20:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2009/09/16/intro-essay-1/</guid>
      <description>I forgot to talk about the first essay assignment in Intro to Philosophy yesterday. Someone remind me tomorrow, especially since it&#39;s due next Tuesday. You can find the assignment here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro Essay 1</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2009/09/10/intro-essay-1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2009 21:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2009/09/10/intro-essay-1-2/</guid>
      <description>I just posted the first essay assignment for Introduction to Philosophy. It&#39;s due September 22.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CT Quiz</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2009/09/02/ct-quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 00:01:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2009/09/02/ct-quiz/</guid>
      <description>Remember the quiz tomorrow in Critical Thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online education more effective than classroom?</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2009/08/20/online-education-more-effective-than-classroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 12:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2009/08/20/online-education-more-effective-than-classroom/</guid>
      <description>Online education more effective than classroom? From the NY Times: &amp;ldquo;A recent 93-page report on online education, conducted by SRI International for the Department of Education, has a starchy academic title, but a most intriguing conclusion: &amp;lsquo;On average, students in online learning conditions performed better than those receiving face-to-face instruction.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;
Surprising.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>