<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Randy Ridenour</title>
    <link>http://randyridenour.net/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Randy Ridenour</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Randy Ridenour</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 20:36:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://randyridenour.net/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Trump and the Johnson Amendment</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2017/05/04/thoughts-on-the-johnson-amendment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 20:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2017/05/04/thoughts-on-the-johnson-amendment/</guid>
      <description>Some thoughts on President Trump&amp;rsquo;s Executive Order on &amp;ldquo;Promoting Free Speech and Religious Liberty&amp;rdquo; that was recently issued:
First of all, the President&amp;rsquo;s executive order doesn&amp;rsquo;t change anything about religious leaders engaging in political action from the pulpit. This is from section 2, the relevant part of the order:
 The Secretary of the Treasury shall ensure, to the extent permitted by law, that the Department of the Treasury does not take any adverse action against any individual, house of worship, or other religious organization on the basis that such individual or organization speaks or has spoken about moral or political issues from a religious perspective, where speech of similar character has, consistent with law, not ordinarily been treated as participation or intervention in a political campaign on behalf of (or in opposition to) a candidate for public office by the Department of the Treasury.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obama&#39;s Economic Record</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2017/03/16/obamas-economic-record/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 07:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2017/03/16/obamas-economic-record/</guid>
      <description>In a recent discussion, one participate claimed that the &amp;ldquo;last eight years of Obamanomics has crippled our struggling state,&amp;rdquo; which I suspect is supported more by a political narrative than an analysis of the data.
The new administration is at least fortunate that the problems handed to them are not at the same level as those handed to the previous administration. During the Obama administration, economic growth was admittedly slow, but considering that he took office on the precipice of what could have been the second great depression, these national numbers look pretty good:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usury in Oklahoma</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2017/03/14/usury-in-oklahoma-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 11:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2017/03/14/usury-in-oklahoma-/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, the House of Representatives of the State of Oklahoma passed HB 1913, a bill giving lenders the ability to charge an Annual Percentage Rate of 205.92% on a $1,500 loan.1
This bill is inconsistent with historical Christian values and should be opposed by conservatives and progressives alike. The practice of taking interest on loans is expressly forbidden in several passages of Scripture:
 Exodus 22:25-27 Leviticus 25:35-38 Deuteronomy 23:19-20; 24:6 Psalm 15:5 Ezekiel 18:7-8; 22:12 Nehemiah 5:6-132  Before 1500, every Christian writer who discussed the practice expressly condemned the practice of charging interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of Fake News</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2016/12/03/the-rise-of-fake-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 10:28:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2016/12/03/the-rise-of-fake-news/</guid>
      <description>NPR has a fascinating, if not troubling, interview with a creator of various fake news sites that began to profilerate during the 2016 presidential election. This part of the interview was particularly telling:
 Well, this isn&amp;rsquo;t just a Trump-supporter problem. This is a right-wing issue. Sarah Palin&amp;rsquo;s famous blasting of the lamestream media is kind of record and testament to the rise of these kinds of people. The post-fact era is what I would refer to it as.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Idol of the Poll</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2016/11/09/the-idol-of-the--poll/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 13:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2016/11/09/the-idol-of-the--poll/</guid>
      <description> The 11th Commandment of Election Season: thou shalt not put thy faith in polls, for they are deceptive creatures, full of empty promises and false hope. {:.big}
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Times</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2016/11/09/interesting-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 05:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2016/11/09/interesting-times/</guid>
      <description>There are three statements that have become known as the &amp;ldquo;Chinese&amp;rdquo; curses, although I should point out that there is no record of any Chinese equivalents. They are three things to wish upon one&amp;rsquo;s enemies. Three things that, on the surface, seem like things that a person should surely want; but appearances, as we all know, are often deceiving.
The first, and the mildest:
 &amp;ldquo;May you live in interesting times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confirmation Bias and the Clinton Foundation</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2016/10/21/the-clinton-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 06:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2016/10/21/the-clinton-foundation/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I showed that claiming that only 5.7% of Clinton Foundation donations goes to charity is essentially false. Although that is indeed the percentage that goes to other charitable organizations, it ignores the fact that the Clinton Foundation is itself a public charity, unlike the Trump Foundation, which is a private foundation.
In response, a friend said that, although my claim was technically true, the majority of Clinton Foundation money goes back to the Clintons through the its two largest program expenditures, the Clinton Global Initiative (CGI) and the Clinton Presidential Library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Uselessness of Political Fact-Checking</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2016/10/20/the-uselessness-of-political-factchecking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 19:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2016/10/20/the-uselessness-of-political-factchecking/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that political fact-checking is largely useless. Either people completely ignore the work of fact-checkers, or the fact-checkers ignore the relevant facts. Today, I saw a claim that Clinton had leaked classified information about the nuclear response window. What was curious was that the post included a link to a snopes.com story explaining that the supposed leak was not classified, but was already public information. The person evidently failed to read the very story to which they had linked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Race, Police Shooting, and Probability</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2016/10/01/black-lives-matter-and-conditional-probabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 10:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2016/10/01/black-lives-matter-and-conditional-probabilities/</guid>
      <description>I just read a Facebook comment by someone who was apparently downplaying the Black Lives Matter movement by pointing out that the police shoot more white Americans than black Americans.
True, but it&amp;rsquo;s a classic error in statistical reasoning. The vast majority of drivers involved in accidents are sober, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t follow that one is more likely to have an accident if one is sober than if drunk. That is, the probability that a person was drunk given that he was in an accident is very low, but the probability that someone will be in an accident given that he is drunk is very high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Parent&#39;s Love</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2015/01/13/a-parents-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 14:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2015/01/13/a-parents-love/</guid>
      <description>Saturday afternoon, protestors lined the bridge at Rogers Avenue and Interstate 44 in Lawton, Oklahoma. They held signs demanding that the children currently detained for illegal immigration be sent back to their home countries.
National Public Radio recently reported on another protest:
 This week outside the southern Arizona town of Oracle, Marla and Bruce Bemis — along with several dozen of their neighbors — were lined up along a road waving American flags and holding signs, as patriotic music occasionally played in the background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mosque in NYC</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/08/16/a-mosque-in-nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2010 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/08/16/a-mosque-in-nyc/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been following the debate over the proposed Mosque near the site of the World Trade Center in New York City. Baptists have historically been champions of religious liberty, and denying Muslims the right to build a house of worship is contrary to historic Baptist principles.
The question to ask is this - would you be happy with a Christian Church at the same location? If so, then do not deny Muslim-Americans the same rights that you are willing to give Christian-Americans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice for Christian Politicians</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/08/11/advice-for-christian-politicians/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 13:17:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/08/11/advice-for-christian-politicians/</guid>
      <description>Advice for Christian Politicians
From Ethics Daily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconciliation and Hope</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/11/07/reconciliation-and-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 10:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/11/07/reconciliation-and-hope/</guid>
      <description>The year that I was born, 1963, was marked by these significant events:
 In April, Martin Luther King was arrested and jailed in Birmingham. In May, “Bull” Connor, the Commissioner of Public Safety in Birmingham used police dogs and fire hoses on a demonstration in Birmingham. In June, Medgar Evers, the NAACP Field Secretary for Mississippi, was murdered outside his home. In August, Martin Luther King delivered his famous “I Have a Dream” speech at the Lincoln Memorial in Washington, D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Election Tomorrow</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/11/03/election-tomorrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 19:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/11/03/election-tomorrow/</guid>
      <description>Go vote!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concern for the Middle Class and Matthew 25</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/10/08/concern-for-the-middle-class-and-matthew-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 16:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/10/08/concern-for-the-middle-class-and-matthew-25/</guid>
      <description>Both presidential candidates seem to be stressing the importance of adopting policies that are good for the middle class. I have to admit that such talk resonates with me, probably because I am a member of the middle class. Today, though, I saw a title of a blog post by Adam Taylor that is making me rethink my assumptions about the priority of the middle class.
It was titled &#34;Just as You Did for the Middle Class, You Also Did for Me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change and Objectivity</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/06/02/climate-change-and-objectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2008 22:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/06/02/climate-change-and-objectivity/</guid>
      <description>The Washington Post reports something today that is unfortunate but unsurprising. NASA&#39;s inspector general has determined that political appointees have controlled and distorted information about research on climate change conducted by NASA scientists. This is why it is so difficult for the layperson like myself to make informed decisions about the severity of the problem and the best response to the problem. Such decisions should be made on the basis of the best science, but what we know about the science has been distorted by those who have already decided what is to be done.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>