<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on Randy Ridenour</title>
    <link>http://randyridenour.net/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on Randy Ridenour</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Randy Ridenour</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 20:29:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://randyridenour.net/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Voices of the Marginalized</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2017/03/09/voices-of-the-marginalized/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 20:29:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2017/03/09/voices-of-the-marginalized/</guid>
      <description>I began teaching the thought of the 12th century philosopher Abelard in medieval philosophy today, and had to tell the story of his relationship with Heloise. Her letters reveal a deep intelligence, a quick wit, and brilliant insight.
How many other brilliant voices have been marginalized over the years?
What wisdom have we missed by silencing them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nietzsche on Military Buildup</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2017/01/13/nietzsche-on-the-military-establishment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 10:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2017/01/13/nietzsche-on-the-military-establishment/</guid>
      <description>And perhaps the great day will come when a people, distinguished by wars and victories and by the highest development of a military order and intelligence, and accustomed to make the heaviest sacrifices for these things, will exclaim of its own free will, &amp;ldquo;We break the sword,&amp;rdquo; and will smash its entire military establishment down to its lowest foundations. Rendering oneself unarmed when one has been the best-armed, out of a height of feeling—that is the means to real peace, which must always rest on a peace of mind; whereas the so-called armed peace, as it now exists in all countries, is the absence of peace of mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancient Philosophy Study Guide</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2016/09/26/ancient-philosophy-study-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 08:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2016/09/26/ancient-philosophy-study-guide/</guid>
      <description>What is the reason for separating Plato&amp;rsquo;s dialogues into Socratic (early) and Platonic (middle) dialogues? Why is Socrates’ method primarily negative? Is there anything that Socrates does (at least implicitly) claim to know? Explain why the Meno is considered a transitional dialogue. Explain Meno&amp;rsquo;s Paradox. How does Plato respond? Although Socrates claims ignorance, he seems to hold some surprising philosophical positions. Explain. Why did Socrates not plead for his life?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evil and Perception</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2015/06/17/evil-and-perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 06:34:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2015/06/17/evil-and-perception/</guid>
      <description>Etgar Keret&amp;rsquo;s new book, The Seven Good Years is a collection of essays concerning the interval between the birth of his son and the death of his father. I was particularly intrigued by this statement from the story on NPR:
 I&amp;rsquo;m pretty good at feeling sorry for myself, [but] &amp;hellip; the fact that he survived the Holocaust always kind of seemed to him that something good had happened to him in life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stories and Community</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2015/05/13/stories-and-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 06:27:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2015/05/13/stories-and-community/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to AJ Lopez for sharing this quote with me.
Instead of telling our vulnerable stories, we seek safety in abstractions, speaking to each other about our opinions, ideas and beliefs rather than about our lives. Academic culture blesses this practice by insisting that the more abstract our speech, the more likely we are to touch the universal truths that unite us. But what happens is exactly the reverse: as our discourse becomes more abstract, the less connected we feel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dostoevsky, Suffering, and the Prayer for the Week</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2015/04/15/dostoevsky-suffering-and-the-prayer-for-the-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 10:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2015/04/15/dostoevsky-suffering-and-the-prayer-for-the-week/</guid>
      <description>This past weekend was a weekend of funerals — two very different people, both with lives that had been cut tragically short. Then, on Tuesday, I learned of two more tragedies involving families in the Army units that I serve. Coincidentally, all of this happens as one of my classes is studying one of the central works on the problem of suffering, the chapter titled in &amp;ldquo;Rebellion&amp;rdquo; in Dostoevsky&amp;rsquo;s masterpiece, The Brothers Karamazov.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santayana on Fanaticism</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2015/03/09/santayana-on-fanaticism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 18:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2015/03/09/santayana-on-fanaticism/</guid>
      <description>Fanaticism consists in redoubling your efforts when you have forgotten your aim. George Santayana, Reason in Common Sense, Vol. I</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Danger of Thinking</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2015/02/22/the-danger-of-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 15:39:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2015/02/22/the-danger-of-thinking/</guid>
      <description>Anyone who has begun to think, places some portion of the world in jeopardy. John Dewey</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Duty of A Philosopher</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2015/01/20/the-duty-of-a-philosopher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 16:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2015/01/20/the-duty-of-a-philosopher/</guid>
      <description>Out of love for mankind, and out of despair at my embarrassing situation, seeing that I had accomplished nothing and was unable to make anything easier than it had already been made, and moved by a genuine interest in those who are dedicated to making everything easy, I conceived it as my task [the task of the philosopher] to create difficulties everywhere. S&amp;oslash;ren Kierkegaard, Concluding Unscientific Postscript</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Penn Jillette on Science and Religion</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2015/01/20/penn-jillette-on-science-and-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2015/01/20/penn-jillette-on-science-and-religion/</guid>
      <description>John Gruber recently posted this interesting quote from Penn Jillette, of Penn and Teller fame:
 There is no god and that’s the simple truth. If every trace of any single religion died out and nothing were passed on, it would never be created exactly that way again. There might be some other nonsense in its place, but not that exact nonsense. If all of science were wiped out, it would still be true and someone would find a way to figure it all out again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Badass Philosophers</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2015/01/13/badass-philosophers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 09:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2015/01/13/badass-philosophers/</guid>
      <description>Best line from a student this week: when I pointed out that women have unfortunately been underrepresented in philosophy, she replied &amp;ldquo;True, but the ones who are there are real badasses.&amp;rdquo; She said that with more than a bit of admiration and pride.
Anyone who doubts that should read a bit about Elizabeth Anscombe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tolerance</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2011/01/11/tolerance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2011 22:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2011/01/11/tolerance/</guid>
      <description>I just finished my paper on the problems with tolerance. Of course, it was a day later than the conference deadline. Now to see how tolerant the conference organizers are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Descartes First Edition</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/11/23/descartes-first-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 20:47:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/11/23/descartes-first-edition/</guid>
      <description>A first edition of Descartes&#39; Principles of Philosophy will be up for auction on December 2. Do you think Sheri will let me bid?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy Street</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/11/17/from-sctv-a-parody-of-sesame-street-called/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 22:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/11/17/from-sctv-a-parody-of-sesame-street-called/</guid>
      <description>From SCTV: a parody of Sesame Street called &amp;ldquo;Philosophy Street.&amp;rdquo;
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ouch</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/11/12/i-dont-quite-know-what-to-say-about-this-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 20:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/11/12/i-dont-quite-know-what-to-say-about-this-video/</guid>
      <description>I don&#39;t quite know what to say about this video, except that it&#39;s not likely the kind of advertising we need to attract the kind of future philosophy students we want.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brief Habits as the Key to Living Forever</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/10/01/brief-habits-as-the-key-to-living-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 11:58:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/10/01/brief-habits-as-the-key-to-living-forever/</guid>
      <description>Nietzsche would like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please!</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/03/29/people-have-always-wanted-philosophers-to-provide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 15:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/03/29/people-have-always-wanted-philosophers-to-provide/</guid>
      <description>People have always wanted philosophers to provide digestible wisdom, yet it is as true now as it was in Plato’s time that disciplined thinking is hard. So next time you sit next to a philosopher on a plane, talk about the movie, not the meaning of life. Anthony Gottlieb</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Happiness of Deep Conversations</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/03/23/the-happiness-of-deep-conversations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2010 14:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/03/23/the-happiness-of-deep-conversations/</guid>
      <description>The New York Times recently reported on a study published in Psychological Science suggesting that people who engage in substantive, meaningful conversations are happier than those who do not.
It appears that Mill was right — it is better to be a dissatisfied Socrates than a satisfied pig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hildebrand Conference</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/02/23/hildebrand-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 15:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/02/23/hildebrand-conference/</guid>
      <description>A conference on the work of Dietrich von Hildebrand is scheduled for May 27-29, 2010 in Rome. There is a student essay contest, and five winners receive lodging, meals, and money for travel expenses to the conference in Rome. The conference website is www.hildebrandlegacy.org.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tradition and Bad Tradition</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/02/15/tradition-and-bad-tradition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 17:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/02/15/tradition-and-bad-tradition/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I posted a quote on the Tumblr page from Jaroslav Pelikan: &#34;The only alternative to tradition is bad tradition.&#34; At the time, I realized it needed some explanation, but posted it anyway. Some comments show that the quote is meaningless without some context.
John Mouracade pointed out that it looks like a false dilemma. A false dilemma is a fallacy committed when one asserts that at least one of two different alternatives must be true, but ignores other alternatives that might also be true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epictetus on Learning</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/02/08/what-is-the-first-business-of-him-who/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 20:48:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/02/08/what-is-the-first-business-of-him-who/</guid>
      <description>What is the first business of him who philosophizes? To throw away self-conceit. For it is impossible for anyone to begin to learn that which he thinks that he already knows. Epictetus, Discourses, Book II, Chapter 17.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change Blindness</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2009/12/14/change-blindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 21:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2009/12/14/change-blindness/</guid>
      <description>A great experiment that shows how little we tend to perceive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kierkegaard&#39;s Mission</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2009/11/24/out-of-love-of-mankind-as-well-as-despair-at-my/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 20:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2009/11/24/out-of-love-of-mankind-as-well-as-despair-at-my/</guid>
      <description>Out of love of mankind, as well as despair at my embarrassing situation, seeing I had not accomplished anything and had been unable to make anything easier than it had already been made, from a genuine interest in those who make everything easy, I conceived it my task to make difficulties everywhere. Kierkegaard, Concluding Unscientific Postscript</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;ve Got Questions!</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2009/11/16/philosophy-program-closed-for-failure-to-find/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 20:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2009/11/16/philosophy-program-closed-for-failure-to-find/</guid>
      <description>Philosophy Program Closed for Failure to Find Answers.
Very funny, in an uncomfortable sort of way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hitchens</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2009/11/15/what-can-be-asserted-without-proof-can-be-rejected/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2009 13:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2009/11/15/what-can-be-asserted-without-proof-can-be-rejected/</guid>
      <description>What can be asserted without proof can be rejected without proof. Christopher Hitchens
What proof does he have for this claim? Is it self-referentially incoherent?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kierkegaard on the Couch</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2009/10/29/kierkegaard-on-the-couch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2009 12:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2009/10/29/kierkegaard-on-the-couch/</guid>
      <description>From The New York Times, I especially like the little Sisyphus figure pushing the giant happy face up the hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Monads</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2009/10/25/the-monads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2009 22:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2009/10/25/the-monads/</guid>
      <description>From the &amp;ldquo;Thoughts, Arguments, and Rants&amp;rdquo; blog, here is a link to a band called &amp;ldquo;The Monads&amp;rdquo; and it&amp;rsquo;s reincarnation, &amp;ldquo;The 21st Century Monads.&amp;rdquo; No educated person could resist songs with titles like &amp;ldquo;The Skeptic Song&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;The Missing Shade of Blues.&amp;rdquo; There&amp;rsquo;s even a song expressing the emotional depths of the academic life: &amp;ldquo;My Paper Was Rejected Again.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>William Alston, 1921-2009</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2009/09/14/william-alston-1921-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2009 00:42:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2009/09/14/william-alston-1921-2009/</guid>
      <description>William Alston died today at the age of 87.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugh Dancy on Philosophy</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2009/08/20/when-you-realize-that-you-that-you-cant-have-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 14:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2009/08/20/when-you-realize-that-you-that-you-cant-have-more/</guid>
      <description>The son of philosopher Jonathan Dancy, explaining on The Tonight Show why he did not choose philosophy as a profession:
When you realize that you that you can&#39;t have more than a five second conversation with your dad before you&#39;re lost, you find another line of work. Hugh Dancy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stanford Encyclopedia Article on the Trinity</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2009/07/24/stanford-encyclopedia-article-on-the-trinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2009 17:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2009/07/24/stanford-encyclopedia-article-on-the-trinity/</guid>
      <description>Dale Tuggy has a new article in The Stanford Encylopedia of Philosophy on the Trinity. In my opinion, The Stanford Encyclopedia is the best reference work in philosophy, not simply the best online reference work in philosophy. I’ve been slowly working on a paper on the Trinity, so I’m grateful to have a nice summary of recent work on the subject. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evangelical Atheists</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/07/15/evangelical-atheists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2008 01:24:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/07/15/evangelical-atheists/</guid>
      <description>There is a very interesting article titled &#34;The Return of Religion&#34; by Roger Scruton today in Axess explaining why the arguments of the the evangelical atheists like Dawkins, Hitchens, and Dennett fail to be persuasive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Kierkegaard</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/06/18/kierkegaard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2008 08:57:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/06/18/kierkegaard/</guid>
      <description>I began reading Kierkegaard&amp;rsquo;s Fear and Trembling yesterday. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take long for me to recall what a friend once said:
Don&#39;t read Kierkegaard in the bathroom; you can&#39;t concentrate on either job. Riley Ross</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>