<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Political on Randy Ridenour</title>
    <link>http://randyridenour.net/tags/political/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Political on Randy Ridenour</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Randy Ridenour</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://randyridenour.net/tags/political/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Abandoning Jubilee — The Structural Causes of Poverty</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/project/jubilee-poverty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/project/jubilee-poverty/</guid>
      <description>The Jubilee law of Leviticus 25 is a radical economic plan which requires a leveling of real assets every fifty years, thus providing an economic structure that regularly dissolves large economic inequalities. It is impossible to follow the letter of the Jubilee law in a modern non-agrarian economy, but this should not free us from the responsibility of adhering to the spirit of the law. A survey of social structures in the United States reveals an economy that is contrary to the spirit of Jubilee, one that not only makes inequalities possible, but makes escaping from poverty nearly impossible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Burwell vs. Hobby Lobby</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2015/01/13/thoughts-on-burwell-vs-hobby-lobby/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 14:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2015/01/13/thoughts-on-burwell-vs-hobby-lobby/</guid>
      <description>Social media was certainly inundated with reactions to yesterday&amp;rsquo;s Supreme Court ruling in Burwell vs. Hobby Lobby. The majority were at the two extremes&amp;mdash;either this was a great victory for religious liberty and a stunning blow to the Obama administration, or it was an unprecedented power-grab by religious conservatives and wealthy corporate America that will only prevent women from getting the health care that they need.
As is generally the case, neither extreme position is correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Triumph of the Will</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2009/08/28/triumph-of-the-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 18:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2009/08/28/triumph-of-the-will/</guid>
      <description>Triumph of the Will, directed by Leni Riefenstahl, is the film that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember in Aesthetics this morning. Roger Ebert, in his 1994 review of a documentary about Riefenstahl asks exactly the right question:
 &amp;ldquo;These are by general consent two of the best documentaries ever made. But because they reflect the ideology of a monstrous movement, they pose a classic question of the contest between art and morality: Is there such a thing as pure art, or does all art make a political statement?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Food Summit</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/06/08/world-food-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2008 12:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/06/08/world-food-summit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The summit on soaring food prices ended last week. For years, I have read that there is plenty of food available to feed everyone on the planet, but the problem was distributing that food. We know from recent events in Myanmar that uncooperative regimes can make aid distribution impossible. Now, though, it seems that there is a genuine food shortage, not simply a problem of distribution. What has changed?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Aid and Religious Freedom</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/05/19/international-aid-and-religious-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 23:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/05/19/international-aid-and-religious-freedom/</guid>
      <description>I am a Baptist who is committed to religious freedom, and I think that the separation of church and state is critical for maintaining religious freedom. I also believe in the value of the classical liberal tradition, in which everyone should have the freedom to choose their own values and act to achieve what they think is good, provided that it does not interfere with another&#39;s ability to do the same.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>