<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Army on Randy Ridenour</title>
    <link>http://randyridenour.net/tags/army/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Army on Randy Ridenour</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Randy Ridenour</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 21:03:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://randyridenour.net/tags/army/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer for the Twenty-Two</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2016/06/22/prayer-for-the-twentytwo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 21:03:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2016/06/22/prayer-for-the-twentytwo/</guid>
      <description>On average, twenty-two veterans commit suicide every day.
God of peace,
We pray for those who
bear the scars of war,
both visible and invisible,
for wounds that cannot be seen
are no less painful to bear,
and peace is but a distant dream
when the war is within one&amp;rsquo;s own soul.
Give them the courage to speak,
and give us to grace to listen.
Amen</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links in Army Enterprise Email</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2015/01/13/links-in-army-enterprise-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 13:58:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2015/01/13/links-in-army-enterprise-email/</guid>
      <description>This will probably be useful to only a few people, but maybe it will help someone who is frantically searching the internet for an answer.
Roughly a year ago, the Army changed its email service to an Exchange Enterprise system. The old address, which I have had for years (decades?) forwards to the new address, which I never can seem to easily remember. It seems, though, that links in forwarded emails are stripped out for security purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Chaplain&#39;s Ultimate Sacrifice</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/12/03/a-chaplains-ultimate-sacrifice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 23:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/12/03/a-chaplains-ultimate-sacrifice/</guid>
      <description>From the Los Angeles Times, a story about Chaplain (Captain) Dale Goetz, the first Chaplain since the Vietnam War to be killed in Combat. Remember to pray for Chaplains and their Chaplain Assistants, as they continue to minister to those who serve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bruised for the Gospel</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/06/14/we-went-to-the-confidence-course-at-ft-sill-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 16:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/06/14/we-went-to-the-confidence-course-at-ft-sill-on/</guid>
      <description>We went to the Confidence Course at Ft. Sill on Saturday. I came back with a black eye, multiple bruises, and a sprained knee. I also had a soldier come to chapel on Sunday who had never attended before. What&#39;s a few bruises for the sake of the Gospel?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visit to Ft. Moultrie</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/04/18/visit-to-ft-moultrie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 20:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/04/18/visit-to-ft-moultrie/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, my class at the chaplain school participated in a staff ride to Charleston. &#34;Staff ride&#34; sounds more impressive than &#34;field trip&#34; but they mean the same thing. The highlight of the visit was a trip to Ft. Moultrie on Sullivan&#39;s Island. The defense of the fort in 1776 was the first major victory over the British in the Revolutionary War. Standing on the high ground at Ft. Moultrie, you can look straight across the harbor and see Ft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Quote From Chaplain School</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/04/18/great-quote-from-chaplain-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2010 13:32:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/04/18/great-quote-from-chaplain-school/</guid>
      <description>From a briefing given by an Army Chaplain about the new Inter-service Chaplain Center that is shared by the Army, Navy, and Air Force:
&#34;We didn&#39;t foresee the challenges that we would have with a building shared by the three services. Each service has its own customs, traditions, and even language. For example, we had to order three different signs for the restrooms - one that said &#39;Latrine&#39; for the Army, &#39;Head&#39; for the Navy, and &#39;Powder Room&#39; for the Air Force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back When I Could Run</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2010/04/13/im-back-at-the-chaplains-school-for-the-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 00:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2010/04/13/im-back-at-the-chaplains-school-for-the-first/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m back at the Chaplains&#39; School for the first time in seven years. One of my classmates for this course asked me today if I was a runner. He said that I looked like someone who passed him on a 5-K in Baghdad. We were stationed on the same base at the same time, so I guess it was me. In honor of those memories, I posted a photo of the 378th Baghdad Army Ten-Miler group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today&#39;s News</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/12/12/todays-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 07:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/12/12/todays-news/</guid>
      <description>Two stories in today’s news caught my attention. First, Britain’s The Independent reports on history’s most famous failed technology predictions. These include a claim from 1977 that no one will need a computer in their home.
The second story, in the Washington Post, is a harrowing account of an assault conducted by U. S. Special Forces soldiers and Afghan commandos on an insurgent stronghold in Afghanistan. Ten of those soldiers will receive the Silver Star today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The End</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/04/27/the-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2008 01:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/04/27/the-end/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s finally over. After a year, I am back at home with Sheri and Rachael. Thanks for all of your thoughts and prayers over the past year. Please continue to pray for:
 The safety of the many soldiers, sailors, airmen, marines, and civilians who remain in harm&#39;s way The psychological health of those who have returned The families who heroically endure long separations The thousands of families who mourn the loss of a loved one who died in combat The people of Iraq, who deserve lives of prosperity and peace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back at Ft. Dix</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/04/19/back-at-ft-dix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 20:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/04/19/back-at-ft-dix/</guid>
      <description>We have made it back to the place where all of our training began - Ft. Dix, New Jersey. After a few days in Kuwait, we began the long process of clearing customs and awaiting transportation. We landed at Maguire Air Force Base on Tuesday. We had to walk across a lawn to get on a bus that was waiting to take us to Ft. Dix. It was wonderful to smell grass once again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Return From Exile</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/04/06/return-from-exile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 14:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/04/06/return-from-exile/</guid>
      <description>This should be my last post from Iraq. Soon, we will move out of our trailers and into some tents, awaiting our flight to Kuwait. As I prepared this morning&#39;s sermon, it struck me that most of the Old Testament was written with this place as a context. I won&#39;t give you the whole sermon, but here are some of the lessons that I&#39;ve learned.
First, the practical lessons: 1) You can lose your tolerance for spicy food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near the End</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/03/31/near-the-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2008 17:03:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/03/31/near-the-end/</guid>
      <description>We have made it to our last full week in Iraq. I was never very interested in prophecy about the future, but lately I have been thinking a lot about eschatology, or the study of last things. Today, I thought about the last time I will change the sheets on the bed here, or the last time I do a PT run down &#34;Sniper Alley.&#34; I wonder if today is the last time that the rockets come in, but given the way things are in Basra right now, I somehow doubt it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/03/24/spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2008 18:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/03/24/spring/</guid>
      <description>It was a beautiful early spring day in Baghdad today. The high was only 99. Fortunately, we&#39;ll be long gone before it gets in the 120&#39;s. On a recent trip, I made it within two miles of the ruins of ancient Babylon. Unfortunately, it was too dangerous to visit the ruins. Tradition maintains that the house that Abraham lived in before he left on his journey of faith is at Tallil, which is in southeastern Iraq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Friday</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/03/21/good-friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2008 17:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/03/21/good-friday/</guid>
      <description>I just finished the Good Friday Tenebrae service. The Tenebrae, or Service of Shadows, has always been a very meaningful service for me. It is a very somber service, as is fitting on Good Friday. A reader reads a passage of Scripture associated with the betrayal, crucifixion, or burial of Jesus, and then blows out one of the candles that provides light for the service. As the readings progress further into the Passion story, the room grows progressively darker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holy Week</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/03/17/holy-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2008 17:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/03/17/holy-week/</guid>
      <description>Palm Sunday has passed, and we are moving into the most solemn period in the church calendar. As we enter this time of reflection concerning the sacrifice of Christ, think about these results of a recent poll by the Pew Research Center. Last August, 54% of Americans polled knew the approximate number of American military personnel that had been killed in Iraq, a percentage that had held steady since the beginning of the war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Palm Sunday</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/03/15/palm-sunday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2008 16:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/03/15/palm-sunday/</guid>
      <description>I guess that it&#39;s time to post some updates. I have been very busy lately, trying to visit all of my soldiers before I turn them over to another chaplain. After my unit had been here for four months, we were given responsibility for about 400 active duty soldiers. They will be here for eight more months after we leave. This week, I made my last troop visitation trip.
Today is the first day of a dust storm that is predicted to last for several days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Is Here</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/03/08/summer-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2008 09:23:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/03/08/summer-is-here/</guid>
      <description>Our winter season has passed, I believe. I know that those of you in the central US won&#39;t feel that low temperatures in the high 30&#39;s really deserve to be called &#34;winter.&#34; Remember, though, that you don&#39;t have to walk 50 yards from your house to the bathroom in the middle of the night.
The high on Monday is supposed to be 93 degrees. So, winter has passed, summer is here, and I don&#39;t recall spring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for Home</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/03/05/preparing-for-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2008 17:19:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/03/05/preparing-for-home/</guid>
      <description>We have been working very hard to turn in any equipment that we won&#39;t need in the time we have left here. It&#39;s exciting to be preparing to go home. Going home presents a new set of challenges for chaplains. I have to make sure that the soldiers understand how to cope with the stresses of plugging back into &#34;normal&#34; life while trying to leave the war behind.
Along those lines, I have read some disturbing articles recently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>300 Days</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/03/02/300-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2008 18:26:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/03/02/300-days/</guid>
      <description>300 days ago, we reported to Ft. Sheridan, Illinois. It was the first leg of what has been a very long and sometimes difficult journey. That journey is nearly over now. Thanks be to God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mustache Month</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/02/29/mustache-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Feb 2008 18:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/02/29/mustache-month/</guid>
      <description>A group of my soldiers declared February to be &#34;Mustache Month.&#34; They all grew mustaches, some fairly impressive, and others decidedly less so. They will shave them tomorrow, March 1. This morning, they gathered for a picture and a small ceremony. For some reason, they asked me if I would say a few words on this solemn occasion.
So, what does one say to mark the passing of a mustache? You can leave your thoughts in a comment if you like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rainy Day</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/02/25/rainy-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 15:56:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/02/25/rainy-day-2/</guid>
      <description>It has been raining all afternoon. The rain turns the clay into mud that has the consistency of peanut butter. I think I&#39;ll sit in the trailer and watch an old Hitchcock film tonight. First, I&#39;ll give a little update about my last two weeks.
I just got back back from a trip north near Saddam&#39;s ancestral home. It reminded me of eastern Colorado with flat brown land and mountains that were visible in the distance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living in Stonehenge</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/02/17/living-in-stonehenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 17:23:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/02/17/living-in-stonehenge/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been back for a week now, and there have been some changes. One change is that my trailer is surrounded by blast walls that are 12 feet high. These concrete monoliths are all over the country. I can imagine some future archaeologist wondering about the purpose of these great stone artifacts, and debating about whether we would have, given time, reached the sophisticated level of the Easter Island culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reassuring?</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/02/09/reassuring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2008 17:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/02/09/reassuring/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m back after enduring another three days of travel. After we arrived at Ali al Salim Air Base in Kuwait, a captain that I was walking with said, &#34;It seems strangely reassuring to be back.&#34; I replied, &#34;You&#39;re right, and that&#39;s more than a little bit sad.&#34; We have all become used to being here, and now the familiarity is reasurring in its own way. We find the familiar to be comfortable, while the unfamiliar is uncomfortable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Back</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/02/06/going-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 12:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/02/06/going-back/</guid>
      <description>Leave was certainly good, but it&#39;s over now. I&#39;m headed back this morning. I apologize to everyone that I couldn&#39;t see while I was home. There just wasn&#39;t enough time to everything I needed to do. I will be back home sometime in May. Until then, pray for peace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home!</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/01/22/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2008 23:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/01/22/home/</guid>
      <description>After three days of traveling, I arrived home yesterday evening. I sure have missed Sheri and Rachael, but I didn&#39;t know how much I&#39;ve missed other things also. Those are things like having a bathroom in the same building as your bedroom, showers that are big enough to turn around in, and being able to just jump in the car and drive anywhere you like. We don&#39;t have any big plans for the next two weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Way Home</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/01/19/on-the-way-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2008 05:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/01/19/on-the-way-home/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s finally time for my leave. I fly from Baghdad to Kuwait today, and probably on back to Oklahoma, via Ireland, Atlanta, and Dallas, tomorrow. I appreciate your prayers for safe travels and a wonderful reunion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snow</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/01/14/snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2008 10:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/01/14/snow/</guid>
      <description>I was surprised to open my trailer door Friday morning and see snow. I never expected to see snow in Baghdad. Evidently, it was the first snow in a century. All the Americans were walking around singing &#34;I&#39;m Dreaming of a White Christmas&#34; or some variation. The Iraqis were just staring. Some of the Iraqis didn&#39;t have a word for it; they just called it &#34;white rain.&#34; People spoke of it being a sign from God, but I never could find out what they thought it signified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tragic News You Won&#39;t Hear on CNN</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/01/06/tragic-news-you-wont-hear-on-cnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2008 17:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/01/06/tragic-news-you-wont-hear-on-cnn/</guid>
      <description>I lost my pianist for chapel last week. He is the division surgeon for the First Cavalry Division. For some reason, he declined to extend his tour to keep playing for my chapel service. So, I&#39;ve been moving through the customary stages of grief: from denial, anger, and bargaining, to where I&#39;m at now, which is some combination of depression and acceptance. I was forced to play the piano myself this morning, forcing even more Soldiers to suffer for their country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New Year</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2008/01/01/the-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 17:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2008/01/01/the-new-year/</guid>
      <description>I would like to write a blog listing the significant events of the year or the major lessons I learned this year, but there is no time. I have to pack tonight to leave on a trip tomorrow to visit some soldiers that are somewhere near the Iranian border. Someone said once that an optimist stays up until midnight to see the new year in, while a pessimist stays up to make sure the old one left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas in Baghdad</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/12/25/christmas-in-baghdad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2007 17:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/12/25/christmas-in-baghdad/</guid>
      <description>It is Christmas Day, 2007, now almost 8:00 in the evening. We have finished dinner, and now I have returned to the solitude of my trailer. After work on Christmas Eve, I organized a little fellowship gathering behind the building. We ate some snacks, threw horseshoes and darts, and talked around a fire. We then went to the palace for the base candlelight service. The Tongan Marine Choir sang, and everyone had a wonderful time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numbers</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/12/20/numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 17:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/12/20/numbers/</guid>
      <description>I think we&#39;re all getting tired. I know I am. In the old days (that&#39;s back when I first joined the Army, 24 years ago), everyone had a countdown, or short-timer&#39;s, calendar. It was a way to keep a running count of how many days you had left in a tour, enlistment, prison-sentence, etc. Some things never change, they just evolve technologically. Now, everyone keeps a spreadsheet that tracks the number of remaining days automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combat Lifesaver Training</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/12/14/combat-lifesaver-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2007 18:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/12/14/combat-lifesaver-training/</guid>
      <description>I have survived my three days of combat lifesaver training. The second day was mostly spent learning how to give IV&#39;s. On the third day, we had a mass-casualty exercise. Giving someone an IV in a classroom is pretty easy. It&#39;s a lot more difficult when the patient is on a stretcher on the ground in the sand as other people are yelling and screaming. My patients survived, though, and don&#39;t quite look like human pincushions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosed in the Nose</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/12/11/hosed-in-the-nose/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2007 18:15:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/12/11/hosed-in-the-nose/</guid>
      <description>I began a three day combat lifesaver&#39;s course today. The highlight of the day was having a six inch rubber hose shoved up my nose. It&#39;s something called a nasal pharyngeal airway, and is designed to keep a patient&#39;s airway open. The sadists teaching the course maintain that you can&#39;t really give one to someone else unless you know how it feels to have it done to you. It goes up the nose, all the way in, until you feel it on the back of your tongue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Defense of Subversiveness</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/12/07/in-defense-of-subversiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2007 17:22:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/12/07/in-defense-of-subversiveness/</guid>
      <description>I recently remarked that a little subversiveness has always been good for the country. Of course, this was meant as a joke, so it&#39;s somewhat foolish for me to try to defend the claim. Whether the claim is true depends on how &#34;subversive&#34; is defined. I&#39;m sure that there are many different lexical definitions of &#34;subversive,&#34; but, if I remember correctly the word comes from the Latin subvertere, meaning literally &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still Here</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/12/04/still-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 18:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/12/04/still-here/</guid>
      <description>I haven&#39;t posted anything in a few days. I can&#39;t access any blog sites from the office computer. They are all blocked. I&#39;m not sure why, but it might be to minimize the possibility of anyone reading Bruce Prescott&#39;s blog on a government machine. They just don&#39;t realize that a little subversiveness is always good for the country. It does make it difficult to post anything new. By the time I get back to the CHU (that stands for &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Trip</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/28/no-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2007 17:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/28/no-trip/</guid>
      <description>Test - Complete this sentence: The shortest distance between two points is ___________.
I got to the airfield to find out that the flight was canceled. Apparently, there were no other flights available. I&#39;m not disappointed for two reasons. First, I found out yesterday that I would have to go up there in two weeks to spend a week or so. The base chaplain there is leaving and is not being replaced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/27/trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 15:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/27/trip/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m off on a trip for a few days. It&#39;s a lot of traveling, so I appreciate your prayers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baptism</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/25/baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2007 17:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/25/baptism/</guid>
      <description>I baptized someone in the 7:00 service this morning. It&#39;s an exciting time in the life of a small congregation, and a good reminder that God continues to work in the lives of people, even here. I have to confess that it was a baptism by sprinkling; a hard thing for a professor at a Baptist college to admit to having done. It&#39;s a good thing I teach philosophy and not Christian Doctrines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Thanksgiving</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/22/happy-thanksgiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2007 15:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/22/happy-thanksgiving/</guid>
      <description>Thanksgiving began with a 10K race here at the camp. I finished in 52 minutes. Needless to say, I did not win. I did have a good time, though. We had a special Thanksgiving service at 11:00, which was followed by dinner. The dining facilities were decorated very nicely. Then, it was back to work. I walked around the work areas and talked with the troops. Everyone is doing very well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekends and Holidays</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/20/weekends-and-holidays/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2007 17:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/20/weekends-and-holidays/</guid>
      <description>Abraham Lincoln said, &#34;I sincerely wish war was a pleasanter and easier business than it is, but it does not admit of holidays.&#34; We have worked through Memorial Day, Independence Day, Labor Day, Columbus Day, Veterans Day, and will work through Thanksgiving and Christmas. My last day off was during the four-day pass that we had in late June. There are occasional feelings of terror and frequent times of hilarity, but the most common emotional state here is simply weariness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suffering?</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/16/suffering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2007 15:27:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/16/suffering/</guid>
      <description>I know that most of America thinks that we are suffering horribly here. In the interests of full disclosure, I feel that I should reveal that tonight, every Friday evening in fact, is steak and lobster night at one of the dining facilities. The other dining facility has their steak on Wednesdays. There is occasional suffering though, sometimes there&#39;s no lobster, just crab legs.
I never thought war would be bad for one&#39;s waistline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golf in Baghdad</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/15/cold-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2007 16:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/15/cold-weather/</guid>
      <description>It got cold . Now, we have highs in the 80&#39;s and low&#39;s in the 50&#39;s. I guess that&#39;s not so cold, but it is a far cry from the 120&#39;s that we had in the summer.
It&#39;s funny what people do here for fun. I have to admire the Australians. Their building is on one of the lakes (This used to be Saddam&#39;s hunting preserve. It has several lakes that he had built.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veterans Day</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/12/veterans-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2007 18:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/12/veterans-day/</guid>
      <description>Veterans Day has come and gone. I attended a very moving ceremony today. Ryan Crocker, the ambassador to Iraq, was the speaker. Generals from Great Britain, Canada, Australia, and the U.S. lay wreaths to commemorate the fallen.
I have conducted many funerals and memorial services of Soldiers since this war began. I remember picking up a book in the bookstore once that contained the last letters written home by many Soldiers and Marines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halfway!</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/10/halfway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2007 14:40:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/10/halfway/</guid>
      <description>Six months ago today, we reported to Ft. Dix, New Jersey for training. Now we can start counting down! Tomorrow is Veterans Day. People nationwide will remember to thank veterans for their service. This year, remember to also thank their families. The burdens they are asked to carry can be unbearable sometimes. If you happen to see my family tomorrow, give them a hug, and tell them it&#39;s from me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Longing for a Dull Life</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/08/longing-for-a-dull-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2007 18:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/08/longing-for-a-dull-life/</guid>
      <description>Life has been interesting here lately. I&#39;m never quite sure what I can post concerning attacks on the base. So, I&#39;ll just say that I spent part of a recent morning face-down in the dirt having some serious prayer time. Fortunately, there were no serious injuries. I am looking forward to going home where the most exciting thing that happens is when the pizza delivery man drives across my yard. There&#39;s much to be said for a long, dull life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reuniting with Families</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/03/reuniting-with-families/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2007 15:54:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/03/reuniting-with-families/</guid>
      <description>Here&#39;s a link to a New York Times article about the difficulties and anxieties that Soldiers and families face upon redeployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cards from Kids</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/02/cards-from-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2007 15:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/02/cards-from-kids/</guid>
      <description>Someone put a bunch of Veterans&#39; Day cards on my desk. They&#39;re all handmade by some kids at an elementary school. I&#39;ve picked out a few:
Joshua writes,
&#34;I wish you luck. I hope you win. I hope you don&#39;t die.&#34;
Thanks, Joshua, I&#39;m with you, especially on that third one!
Jocelyn writes,
&#34;Hi. My name is Jocelyn Miller, age 10. I hope you have a safe trip to Iraq and don&#39;t get hurt while you&#39;re there and get to come home soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different Traditions</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/01/different-traditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 14:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/11/01/different-traditions/</guid>
      <description>One thing I love about the chaplaincy is the chance to associate with, worship with, and learn from people from different traditions in Christianity. Today, I chaired a monthly meeting of the ministers from the various congregations. In attendance were a minister from the Gospel congregation, an Episcopal priest, a Roman Catholic priest, a Southern Baptist, and me. The Episcopalian led the devotional, and we had a wonderful time.
It&#39;s nice to be in a place where denominational differences are used as icebreakers to build bridges to other people, not to isolate us from the rest of the Church.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Day in the Life...</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/10/28/another-day-in-the-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2007 19:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/10/28/another-day-in-the-life/</guid>
      <description>The events of the day, which was a typical Sunday:
0500 - Wake up, shave, get dressed for Physical Training
0600 - Run with a soldier who asked me to pace him on the 2 mile physical fitness test run.
0700 - Morning chapel service.
0800 - Breakfast with a group of other chaplains.
0900 - Go to the office, have a devotional and prayer time, read the morning e-mail, and come up with a &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/10/26/update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2007 18:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/10/26/update/</guid>
      <description>I haven&#39;t had much time to post anything recently. I&#39;ve been busy getting to know my 250 new soldiers. We have had some gorgeous weather lately. Lows have been in the high 60&#39;s with highs in the low 90&#39;s. It definitely feels cool in the mornings. I&#39;m scheduled to go home on leave in January. I&#39;m not sure if I can survive the cold Oklahoma wind in January after seven months in the desert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/10/19/prayer-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2007 16:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/10/19/prayer-2/</guid>
      <description>The trouble with being a chaplain is that you can&#39;t talk much about the details of your work. There are some issues that you could pray for, though. Pray that we will all experience more open communication, find healthy ways to address conflict, and develop renewed attitudes of respect and understanding for each other.
 Pray also for some time to write a sermon for Sunday...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Times</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/10/13/busy-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2007 19:42:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/10/13/busy-times/</guid>
      <description>I haven&#39;t posted anything in a few days. It&#39;s been very busy here. There was a large attack recently that was reported in the news. More than a dozen mortars were lobbed in, and there were several casualties. One of my soldiers was able to treat an injured officer, stabilizing him until the ambulance arrived. No one in my unit was hurt.
We also are receiving four new companies. That means my &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Army Ten-Miler</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/10/08/the-army-ten-miler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2007 16:20:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/10/08/the-army-ten-miler/</guid>
      <description>The Army Ten-Miler was held Sunday in Washington. It is the largest ten-mile race in the world; 26,000 were expected to run. Thirty military amputees ran the race, calling themselves the &#34;Parts Missing in Action&#34; group. A great testimony to the perserverance and strength of will of the American Soldier.
We had an official ten-miler shadow run here on the base. Seven of us ran, and all seven completed the race.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Text, New Meaning</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/10/06/old-text-new-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 13:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/10/06/old-text-new-meaning/</guid>
      <description>I generally use the Revised Common Lectionary when I preach. The lectionary is a set of readings for use in the service on Sunday. It is on a three year cycle, and each day has an Old Testament reading, a Psalm, a reading from the Gospels, and a reading from the rest of the New Testament. Lectionary use is fairly rare in my tradition, but I think that it has two advantages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encountering the Enemy</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/10/03/encountering-the-enemy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2007 14:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/10/03/encountering-the-enemy/</guid>
      <description>I recently attended a screening of an interesting documentary, Meeting Resistance. A British and and an American interviewed a dozen insurgents about their reasons for fighting the Americans. One thing that is clear upon watching the film is the difficulty of combating an insurgency that is composed of small, relatively independent cells. Another difficulty is countering the insurgents&#39; message that the Americans are simply an army of occupation. That makes winning popular support for the coalition and the Iraqi security forces more difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/29/updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2007 12:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/29/updates/</guid>
      <description>I have some updates to things that I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned in the past.
 I left out the Japanese and the Koreans from my list of represented nations. The weather now is a gorgeous 100 degrees, with lows in the 70&amp;rsquo;s. If you don&amp;rsquo;t think that 100 degrees is gorgeous, visit Kuwait in July. The &amp;ldquo;Ring of Fire&amp;rdquo; has now cooled. The kids at the clinic are still adorable, and my soldiers love visiting there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An International Base</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/27/an-international-base/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2007 14:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/27/an-international-base/</guid>
      <description>One thing that&#39;s interesting is the number of different countries represented here. Americans are by far the most common. There are a large number of Australians stationed here, though. I&#39;ve enjoyed talking to them. Other countries are represented by one or two. There are a few Brits, but most of them are stationed farther south. There are soldiers from central European and Central American countries. A Marine unit from the Kingdom of Tonga arrived recently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks NorthHaven</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/25/thanks-northhaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2007 09:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/25/thanks-northhaven/</guid>
      <description>I am blessed to be a member of a great church, NorthHaven Church in Norman, Oklahoma. The church just moved into a new building, and I&#39;m sorry that I&#39;ve missed the first Sundays there. I was reading the blog written by my pastor, Mitch Randall, and saw a comment left by a new member. She wrote about how she had finally found a home, and I know exactly how she feels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthdays</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/22/birthdays/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2007 12:13:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/22/birthdays/</guid>
      <description>We gather every month for a birthday party. All those who have birthdays for September will be honored. We have a cake to eat, and we&#39;ll probably play some volleyball. Part of the challenge for everyone is keeping in good spirits when those important events of life occur. It&#39;s hard having a birthday, anniversary, or other significant event happen while you&#39;re away from home. You can celebrate with your adopted family here, but it&#39;s not the same as being home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evening in the Green Zone</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/21/evening-in-the-green-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2007 13:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/21/evening-in-the-green-zone/</guid>
      <description>I went to visit some soldiers in the International Zone (otherwise known as the Green Zone) yesterday. It&#39;s a very different place to be stationed. The embassy is there, so there are a lot of civilians. It&#39;s not an isolated compound like the military bases, so you really feel like you are in an international city, not just an American outpost.
We spent an hour or so playing dominos and relaxing by one of the embassy pools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Night</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/19/movie-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2007 11:25:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/19/movie-night/</guid>
      <description>We have organized a movie night here at the headquarters. There&#39;s not all that much to do here except work, eat, and exercise. There&#39;s not a real theater on the base, so we thought that watching a movie and having some popcorn will be good for people&#39;s spirits. My office had a big screen TV in it that I never used, so we moved it into one of the larger offices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall is in the Air</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/18/fall-is-in-the-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2007 05:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/18/fall-is-in-the-air/</guid>
      <description>Everyone is loving the weather. We can feel a little nip in the air, and it feels like we&#39;re moving into fall. The high is only supposed to be 104 today with a low of 79 tonight. That might not seem so cool, but remember it was 125 when we got here... and, as they say, it&#39;s a dry heat.
 The cooler temperatures also seem to have made a difference in the moods of people I see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks, Westwood Elementary!</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/16/thanks-westwood-elementary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2007 07:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/16/thanks-westwood-elementary/</guid>
      <description>My unit is honored to have been adopted by the Westwod Elementary School in Oklahoma City. You can view their web page at http://www.okcps.org/es/westwood/. It means a lot to us to know that people are thinking of us, and want to help. Thanks, Dr. Jan, and all of the faculty, staff and students at Westwood. When I get back from Iraq, I&#39;m going to visit you and give my thanks in person!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jokes and Prayers</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/15/jokes-and-prayers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2007 15:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/15/jokes-and-prayers/</guid>
      <description>Thanks for the jokes. So far, they have come from my sister, Rhonda, and her husband, Mark. I&#39;m not sure I can use the Quaker jokes. I might offend any Quakers in the unit. On the other hand, I suppose there aren&#39;t many good Quakers in the Army, it being a pacifist tradition...
As you can see from one of his responses below, he is asking for prayer for my sister as she undergoes medical tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jokes</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/13/jokes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2007 16:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/13/jokes/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, tensions can run pretty high at staff meetings. The staff officers work long hours and never get a whole day off. We each try to get away a half-day once a week, but that isn&#39;t always possible. When we mobilized in May, I began telling a joke or a humorous story at each staff meeting. My stories are pretty popular, and the presentation order quickly changed so that I closed the meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September 11</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/11/september-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 17:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/11/september-11/</guid>
      <description>It is September 11, and we took some time out of the day to reflect upon the events that led to our being here. As we did, events happened here that vividly reminded us how fragile our lives are. War and disease both have the consequence of forcing us to rethink our priorities. I am a materialist from a materialistic culture, but the only thing I really want is to go home to see my family again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good News and Bad News</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/07/good-news-and-bad-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2007 13:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/07/good-news-and-bad-news/</guid>
      <description>As the old line goes, I have some good news and some bad news. The bad news first: it&#39;s boring. I&#39;m on one of the largest bases in the country, and there is very little to do here. I was talking to one of my soldiers recently; and he said that it could be worse, we could be in prison. Then he said, &#34;There&#39;s a wall around us, with barbed wire on top, and I don&#39;t do anything except work, eat, sleep, and go to the gym.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethics and War - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/06/ethics-and-war-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2007 09:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/06/ethics-and-war-part-2/</guid>
      <description>War has always been morally complex. In freshman philosophy and upper-level ethics courses, we dream up wild ethical dilemmas that we use to test different moral theories. They are things like being forced to kill an innocent person or let other innocent people die. These dilemmas are interesting to talk about; but we don&#39;t worry about them too much, since we rarely face choices like that in normal life. Unfortunately, those dilemmas are common enough in war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need to Restock Larry&#39;s Mart</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/05/need-to-restock-larrys-mart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2007 11:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/05/need-to-restock-larrys-mart/</guid>
      <description>The stock at Larry&amp;rsquo;s Mart is getting low. If any groups need a project, we could use some supplies. Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of suggestions:
Toiletries:
 Body Wash Deodorant Shampoo Conditioner Razor Blades Nail Clippers And Files Bath Sponges Shaving Cream Eyeglass Cleaner Floss Foot Powder. Baby Powder Lotion Q-Tips  Snacks:
 Peanut Butter Crackers Cheese Crackers Various Kinds Of Nuts Cereal Bars Slim Jims Beef Jerky Ritz Bits Fruit Rollups And Other Fruit Snacks Microwave Popcorn Chips Crystal Light On-The-Go Packages Coffee  Over-The-Counter Medication (Generics Are Fine):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Christian in the Army</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/02/a-christian-in-the-army/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2007 14:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/09/02/a-christian-in-the-army/</guid>
      <description>To be honest, sometimes it is difficult reconciling Christianity with military service. People disagree about Jesus&#39; attitude towards war, but I think that people like John Howard Yoder and Walter Wink make a good case. The most obvious problem is that, regardless what we think Jesus meant, the early church was clearly committed to pacifism. That&#39;s not the problem that strikes me today, though.
One of the lectionary texts for today is the story of the banquet in Luke 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Trip</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/31/another-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2007 16:33:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/31/another-trip/</guid>
      <description>I went to Taji last night to visit three soldiers. It was the wildest helicopter ride that I&#39;ve ever had. We went up, then down, then rolled onto the left side, then the right side, then shot some flares out, then repeated the cycle for an hour. Just when I thought I was going to lose my lunch, we landed. The guys there were grateful for the visit, so I guess it was worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethics and War</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/29/ethics-and-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2007 12:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/29/ethics-and-war/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s been a relatively easy couple of days here. That has given me some time to work on a small project for the corps chaplain&#39;s office. There are two chaplain&#39;s assistants who are headed to a meeting to discuss ethics issues in the Iraq and Afghanistan theaters, and I have been asked to provide some background material for them. I think that most of the discussion about ethical lapses in the current war miss an important point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Little Philosophical Theology</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/26/a-little-philosophical-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2007 16:37:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/26/a-little-philosophical-theology/</guid>
      <description>Tim Youmans left a comment to a previous posting, so I had an opportunity to browse over to his blog. I saw a post concerning a major issue in philosophy of religion, and I couldn&#39;t help but leave a comment. It was sure nice to get to say something about philosophy. I&#39;m missing the excitement of the first few weeks of class right now. We have our own kind of excitement here, but it&#39;s just not the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hearing from Home</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/24/hearing-from-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2007 13:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/24/hearing-from-home/</guid>
      <description>I had to call the office about a student&#39;s grade from last semester. I got to talk to several people back at the university. It was sure nice to hear some voices from home. I also got several messages and pictures from colleagues.
The best, though, is that I now have a working internet connection in my trailer. So, Sheri and I can make video calls through Skype. It&#39;s nice to be able to see the person as you speak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bullets in the Air</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/21/bullets-in-the-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2007 12:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/21/bullets-in-the-air/</guid>
      <description>It was an exciting night last night. I had a Bible study in the office at 2000, and caught the 2100 bus back to my quarters. I live in a trailer pretty close to the edge of the camp. As I was walking from the bus stop through this open area to my trailer, a firefight (Armyese for &#34;gun battle&#34;) broke out outside the camp. I walked along watching tracers shoot through the sky in the distance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Is Over...</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/19/sunday-is-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2007 14:16:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/19/sunday-is-over/</guid>
      <description>We just finished the prayer service at the battalion. This is a big base, and there are a lot of different services for different faith groups. So, there&#39;s a service for everyone, but some of my soldiers either don&#39;t feel that they can get away from the office, or they don&#39;t want to go to the chapel. So, we have our own small service at the battalion headquarters.
Sermon preparation is a challenge here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May God Forgive Me</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/18/may-god-forgive-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 07:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/18/may-god-forgive-me/</guid>
      <description>I may have committed the unpardonable sin. I threw two boxes of books in the dumpster. Or more accurately, I had the sergeant throw two boxes of books in the dumpster. This is the Army, after all.
Before I got here, I think I have only thrown away one book in my entire life. It was a copy of William Peter Blatty&#39;s book, The Exorcist, that I read in high school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer: The Last Act of a Desperate Believer</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/15/prayer-the-last-act-of-a-desperate-believer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2007 09:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/15/prayer-the-last-act-of-a-desperate-believer/</guid>
      <description>War has probably always presented a good opportunity to reinvigorate one&#39;s prayer life. There are some large mosques nearby, and if you are out at the right time, you can hear the call to prayer very clearly. I&#39;ve decided to use the sound of gunfire as a call to prayer. Several times a day, I hear gunfire from somewhere outside the walls, and try to say a prayer for those on both sides of the conflict, and also for those who are caught in the middle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Wave</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/10/cool-wave/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2007 12:59:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/10/cool-wave/</guid>
      <description>After the desolate pictures of the desert in Kuwait, I thought you should see what difference some water makes. This is a picture from my last trip. We flew over this very nice date orchard and a few farms.
 I was out running this morning when an explosion shook the ground. I think I set a personal best time for three miles. It&#39;s amazing what a little motivation can do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Clinic</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/09/the-clinic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2007 10:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/09/the-clinic/</guid>
      <description>Here are two pictures from the clinic that we go to on Saturdays. The first is a child who has a new toy. The second is of a group of teenagers who work there. They were just finishing up building a new wheelchair out of a plastic outdoor chair.
We could use some more toys, and we could really use some shoes, men&#39;s, women&#39;s and children&#39;s, to give away.
Pray for those who are struggling who just want a better life in a peaceful country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trips</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/08/trips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2007 05:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/08/trips/</guid>
      <description>I don&#39;t have much time to post anything today. I&#39;m leaving on a trip to visit some soldiers on another base. I don&#39;t think Sheri likes it much when I travel; for some reason, she wants me to keep the excitement level to a minimum. Here&#39;s a view of Baghdad from the helicopter on my last trip:
Thanks for your prayers, and I&#39;ll have another post in a couple of days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Office</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/07/44/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2007 05:47:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/07/44/</guid>
      <description>I managed to get a picture on today. Here is a picture of me in front of the office.
I&#39;ve really become attached to the exterior decorating scheme. I wonder how Sheri would feel about putting sandbags around the house when I get home?
I&#39;ve also found something that I might put in my office. The last vehicle in a convoy has a sign in Arabic and English that says &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ring of Fire</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/06/ring-of-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2007 15:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/06/ring-of-fire/</guid>
      <description>I just finished supper, and have come back to the office. I&#39;m starting a weekly Bible study this week, and we&#39;ll have our first meeting for the night shift tonight.
I&#39;m both amazed and amused how soldiers can take something unpleasant and find a way to lift everyone&#39;s spirits. For example, I don&#39;t know how many of you have had the pleasure of using a Port-a-John that&#39;s been sitting in the sun on a 120 degree day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being an Army Chaplain</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/04/being-an-army-chaplain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2007 15:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/08/04/being-an-army-chaplain/</guid>
      <description>A former student, Caleb, left a comment to one of the last posts. Caleb is in seminary now, and is a chaplain candidate in the Oklahoma National Guard. There is a great shortage of military chaplains, especially in the Guard and Reserves. I&#39;m grateful for young ministers who are willing to consider and accept the call to chaplaincy service.
I need to point out that my blog posts don&#39;t really give you a good feeling for what I specifically do during the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Larry&#39;s Mart - Baghdad Branch</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/31/larrys-mart-baghdad-branch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2007 14:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/31/larrys-mart-baghdad-branch/</guid>
      <description>One of the best ministries that we have is essentially a convenience store in our office. People send care packages to us, and we stock the shelves with toiletries, snacks, writing paper, envelopes, and other goodies. We also have a bookcase filled with paperbacks, and another shelf full of DVD&#39;s that we sign out. On the wall is a dart board, and we have a TV and refrigerator full of cold water and Gatorade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toys and Goodies</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/28/toys-and-goodies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2007 13:09:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/28/toys-and-goodies/</guid>
      <description>I went to a clinic today with a box of toys to pass out to the kids. It was a lot of fun, and I and and the Chaplain&#39;s Assistant are looking forward to the next trip. They have a nursing training program, a vision health training program, and someone training to do basic dental work. If you know any dentists who would like to donate some dental cleaning equipment, then let me know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Office</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/27/the-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2007 10:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/27/the-office/</guid>
      <description>I am on a very large base in Baghdad. It was a hunting preserve of Saddam&#39;s, but he was probably only here 7 or 8 times total. My office is in a small trailer, where we provide cold bottles of water to soldiers and give them a place to relax. The cold water is important since the temperature is currently 118 degrees and will continue to rise through August.
 I was going to attach a picture of the office, but I&#39;m having trouble getting it to upload.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunrise in Kuwait.</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/25/sunrise-in-kuwait/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 05:42:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/25/sunrise-in-kuwait/</guid>
      <description>The picture yesterday looked pretty barren. I have to admit, though, that the sunrises and sunsets over the desert were beautiful. I&#39;m preparing a sermon for Sunday on the role of the desert in Scripture. Significant events happened in the desert to Moses, Jesus, and others. Maybe God has things of spiritual significance in store for us.
Pray for peace...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>View from Kuwait</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/24/view-from-kuwait/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2007 12:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/24/view-from-kuwait/</guid>
      <description>Here is a picture of the scenery in Kuwait...
This is the view from one of the tents that I stayed in there. It makes the Oklahoma/Texas pandhandle look like paradise! I&#39;m sure that there are much prettier parts of the country, but the Army didn&#39;t send me to any of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Chapel</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/22/sunday-chapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2007 07:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/22/sunday-chapel/</guid>
      <description>I went to chapel this morning. For some reason, there is an expectation that the chaplains will attend chapel! It was a good service, although it was a bit strange to see the ushers all wearing 9 mm handguns. Maybe churches at home would have more success in meeting their annual budgets if the ushers would start packing heat.
Blessings...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baghdad</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/20/baghdad/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2007 15:34:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/20/baghdad/</guid>
      <description>We made it to our destination, finally. It has taken some time to set up computer access, which is why this post is late. I need to post some pictures sometime so that you can see the difference between Baghdad and Kuwait. We have trees! I won&#39;t talk about specific details of any operations, but I can tell you that the place that I am staying is quite safe. Thanks for all of your prayers, and I&#39;ll let you know soon about the ministries that I will be starting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Praying</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/14/praying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2007 11:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/14/praying/</guid>
      <description>We had another great prayer time last night. Thanks you all of you who joined us back at home. We&#39;ll try to pray at the same time today, but we might not be able to do so. Today is a day that prayer will be needed, but I can&#39;t share any more.
Blessings...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/13/prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2007 03:53:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/13/prayer/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday was a slow day. We had a very hard three days at the range, with little sleep. So, we enjoyed a slow day yesterday. I had a prayer meeting last night at 2130 (9:30 pm) and will also have one at the same time tonight and tomorrow. Who said Baptists don&#39;t have revivals anymore! Eight people were there, and we had a good prayer time.
Thank you for your prayers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Training</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/12/more-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2007 03:45:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/12/more-training/</guid>
      <description>We went to a training area in the middle of the desert for the last three days. It was just a few tents in the middle of the sand. There, we had some classes, the soldiers went to a short-range marksmanship range, and we went on a convoy exercise that had a bunch of IED&#39;s, civilians in a town, and other scenarios.
The weather was hot (big surprise, there), and the air conditioning wasn&#39;t working in the tents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rollovers</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/08/rollovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2007 13:08:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/08/rollovers/</guid>
      <description>I hear that the pastor wants to stick the congregation members. I&#39;m not sure he&#39;s going to get any volunteers. I think my congregation here just decided that the IV would be less painful than one of my sermons!
Today we had fun with a vehicle rollover simulator. Rollovers are a significant cause of injuries and death. The simulator is like a ride at the fair. It is the cab from a Hummvee that has been mounted on a machine that spins it on an axis that runs horizontally through the middle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Aid</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/07/first-aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2007 16:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/07/first-aid/</guid>
      <description>First aid training today... I learned how to give an emergency tracheotomy with a pocket knife, and I gave someone an IV. Only got to practice the IV on an actual volunteer. For some reason, no one would volunteer for the other procedure. Sheri knows that I have a queasy stomach, so I&#39;m really surprised I managed to do the IV. It&#39;s one of those things that I&#39;m glad I can do, but hope I never have the chance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driven to Drink</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/06/driven-to-drink/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2007 17:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/06/driven-to-drink/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve become a heavy drinker. I always travel with a water bottle in hand; and when I finish that one, I start another. The camp command requires that whenever a soldier becomes a heat casualty (heatstroke or heat exhaustion), the core body temperature must be taken immediately. I&#39;ll just say that this involves cutting away the back side of the uniform and putting a thermometer in places that we won&#39;t discuss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kuwait</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/04/kuwait/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2007 07:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/07/04/kuwait/</guid>
      <description>After about 24 hours of travel time (flying, waiting in terminals, etc.), we arrived in Kuwait. We will be here for nearly two weeks. It is hot, sandy, with more heat and a little (no, a lot) more sand. I wish I could describe how it looks. There are no trees, no grass, no vegetation at all. There is just sand. We have had a sandstorm for two days now. I feel like a bit player in an old Foreign Legion film.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the Air</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/30/in-the-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2007 20:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/30/in-the-air/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s travel day today. We got to the airfield just after midnight, and the plane left at 4:30 AM. We had a stop to refuel in Canada, then flew to Germany. I got to see icebergs from the plane as we left Newfoundland. It&#39;s now 4:15 PM EDT, but just after 9 PM local time in Germany. The weather is nice and cool in both Newfoundland and Germany. We&#39;re wondering what the contrast will feel like when we reach our final destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/29/leaving/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2007 22:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/29/leaving/</guid>
      <description>We&#39;re leaving tomorrow. We had a great picnic today with the unit and some of the families. Members of my church, NorthHaven Church in Norman, quickly responded to a plea for some funds to finance the meal. We cooked hamburgers, hot dogs, pulled pork, ribs, and chicken. We played volleyball and tossed some horseshoes. It was a great meal and a fun time. Everyone asked me to express their appreciation to the church.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Days in Philadelphia</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/26/four-days-in-philadelphia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2007 21:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/26/four-days-in-philadelphia/</guid>
      <description>Sheri, Rachael, and I are spending four great days in Philadelphia. It has sure been nice to spend some time with them and to get away from all things Army. We spent the day today in the Philadelphia Art Museum. They have an excellent collection of Asian art, Medieval art, and an especially nice collection of 20th century art. I was particularly happy to see some well-known works by Duchamp and Mancusi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pass!</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/23/pass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2007 15:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/23/pass/</guid>
      <description>We leave today for a four-day pass! Tomorrow will be the first day off that we have had since May 6. Everyone is tired, but in great spirits and excited to see our families. Sheri and Rachael are flying to Philadelphia to meet me there, and we will spend four great days together. Very soon after that, I&#39;ll be flying east. I think everyone in the unit is ready to move on to new and exciting things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Exercise</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/21/final-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2007 00:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/21/final-exercise/</guid>
      <description>We just finished a three day exercise that was the last major training event we will have before we leave the states. The hours were long, so everyone is pretty tired. The exercise involves simulations of different scenarios that each section could face. Someone watches your response, and evaluates your actions. For me, the tasks were a suicide threat, a conscientious objector, and responding to some casualties. We did well, but I hope that we don&#39;t have to do it in real life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home, Sweet Home...</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/17/home-sweet-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2007 10:43:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/17/home-sweet-home/</guid>
      <description>We moved out of the tents and back to our barracks. That means we&#39;ve moved back to the land of porcelain toilets and good internet connections. One is low-tech, the other high-tech, but both definitely beat no-tech. Everyone is excited to be out of the woods (literally, not figuratively). At our last staff meeting at the FOB, I shared Exodus 8:20 as the passage for the day:
&#34;Then the LORD said to Moses, &#39;Rise early in the morning and present yourself before Pharaoh as he goes out to to the water, and say to him, &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost Finished</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/14/almost-finished/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 18:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/14/almost-finished/</guid>
      <description>Training is almost over. We just finished a three day exercise that covered base defense and combat convoy operations. Since chaplains can&#39;t carry weapons, I was tasked to be on the first aid/litter team for the base defense part and a driver on the convoy. It was fun, but a little stressful. When ordered, we drove our Humvee to the area where the casualty was, began first aid treatment, then loaded up the casualty on the stretcher and drove him back to the field hospital.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/12/thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2007 08:43:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/12/thanks/</guid>
      <description>Thanks for the comments and messages. It&#39;s nice hearing from all of you, and each comment lifts my spirits more than you can know. Right now, my computer access is fairly limited, so I can&#39;t respond to each one.
Blessings...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seek and Ye Shall Find...</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2007 18:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/10/seek-and-ye-shall-find/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s been a couple of days since I&#39;ve been able to get online. Friday, I went on a dismounted (no vehicles, the Army still speaks in horse cavalry terms) IED defense range. We were simulating a combat patrol down a road and into a village, and encountered three IED&#39;s on the route. When we found one, we were to take appropriate action.
I was going along with a group led by a young Staff Sergeant, when we spotted an IED.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training for IED&#39;s</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/07/training-for-ieds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 07:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/07/training-for-ieds/</guid>
      <description>A good deal of our training here is designed to prepare us for one of the primary threats: the improvised explosive device, or IED. When we go anywhere outside the FOB (forward operating base), we have to move in a tactical convoy of at least two vehicles. Each vehicle has a driver, a person in the front passenger seat who is on the radio, and a gunner who stands up in the center hatch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rainy Day</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/06/rainy-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2007 00:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/06/rainy-day/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday was a rainy day at the FOB. Rain is always a positive thing in Scripture, a sign of God&#39;s favor. Here, it has positive and negative aspects. Everything is muddy, and the rain comes through the open gunner&#39;s hatches on the vehicles when we are in a convoy. On the other hand, it is much cooler, and I&#39;m sure that in a month, we will be remembering 70 degree temperatures with fondness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Services at the Range</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/03/services-at-the-range/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2007 22:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/03/services-at-the-range/</guid>
      <description>I went to a range where my soldiers were qualifying on heavy machine guns and light automatic weapons. Since it was Sunday, we had services at the range. I had to conduct several services with small groups as they were available. Here&amp;rsquo;s a picture of the altar. I dropped the brushguard on our Humvee and placed the cross and communion cup on it. The sermon text was John 15:13, &amp;ldquo;No one has greater love than this, to lay down one&amp;rsquo;s life for one&amp;rsquo;s friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anniversary Apart</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/02/anniversary-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2007 15:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/02/anniversary-apart/</guid>
      <description>Today is our anniversary. I have been married to Sheri for 23 years, and am looking forward to at least 50 more. I thank God every day for her, and the wedding pronouncement is correct: what God has brought together, no one, not even the Army, can bring apart.
I love you, still and always...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laundry Day</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/02/laundry-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2007 15:28:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/02/laundry-day/</guid>
      <description>Today is laundry day! Sheri, my wife, knows that I have never been excited about laundry before. Since we don&#39;t have washers at the training FOB (Forward Operating Base), we get to go back to main post to do laundry. At our building there, we also have air conditioning and a good internet connection. So, for the moment, laundry is a good thing.
It&#39;s amazing how one&#39;s priorities change relative to the circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bullets and Sleep</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/01/bullets-and-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 20:41:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/01/bullets-and-sleep/</guid>
      <description>The unit had a night fire last night, and returned to the compound (affectionately known as cell block B) last night after midnight. We then got up at 4:00 this morning to go get smallpox shots and the second round of the anthrax shots. They then went to another live fire range immediately after the shots. I&#39;m not sure that giving real bullets to a bunch of ticked-off soldiers with less than four hours sleep is a good idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthday Party</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/01/birthday-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 03:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/01/birthday-party/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday was my birthday. We convoyed from our beautiful home in the woods (see picture) to the main part of the base. The soldiers went to practice firing their weapons, and I walked down to the main chapel to pick up some communion supplies. When we got back, I stepped into the tent for a moment, and stepped out into a crowd. Somehow, the soldiers had managed to get a decorated cake out into the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Army, One More Time</title>
      <link>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/01/welcome-to-the-army-one-more-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 02:56:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randyridenour.net/2007/06/01/welcome-to-the-army-one-more-time/</guid>
      <description>I teach philosophy at Oklahoma Baptist University in Shawnee, Oklahoma, but have recently been mobilized as a chaplain for a unit that will soon deploy to Iraq. I hope to use this blog to let family (especially my loving, and much loved, wife and daughter) and friends know what I am doing.
For security reasons, I will not post specific details, but only general information concerning my experiences as an Army chaplain.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>